Jonah Sherman Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 7. Graphic Materials, 1847 - 1987; 7; Boxes: 122 - 127
  - Subseries 7.1: 300th Anniversary Parade, 1987; 7.1; Box: 122
    - Poughkeepsie's 300th Anniversary Parade - Negatives, 1987 June (Folder 17, Box 122)
  - Subseries 7.2: Dutchess County Historical Society Photos, 1847 - 1980; 7.2; Boxes: 122 - 124
    - Academy Street [6 photos], circa 1890 - 1915 (1980 reprints) (Folder 18, Box 122)
    - Arnolds Chair Factory [2 photos], 1891 - 1892 (1980 reprints) (Folder 19, Box 122)
    - Bent Barnes Alfred Scott [2 photos], 1891 (1980 reprints) (Folder 20, Box 122)
    - Bowne Memorial Hospital J.B. Camp, now Dutchess Community College Bowne Hall, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 21, Box 122)
    - Cannon Street [4 photos], 1863 - 1917 (1980 reprints) (Folder 22, Box 122)
    - Churches and Houses of Worship [17 photos], 1857 - 1965 (1980 reprints) (Folder 23, Box 122)
    - Church Street [6 photos], 1907 - 1914 (1980 reprints) (Folder 24, Box 122)
    - College Hill - Building, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 25, Box 122)
    - College Hill on Fire, 1917 February 17 (1980 reprint) (Folder 26, Box 122)
    - College Hill - Dudley Memorial Shelter, 1944 (1980 reprint) (Folder 27, Box 122)
    - Delafield Street - Elting House, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 28, Box 122)
    - Fallkill Creek, 1899 (1980 reprint) (Folder 29, Box 122)
    - Fire Houses [8 photos], 1901 - 1908 (1980 reprints) (Folder 30, Box 122)
    - Garden Street, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 31, Box 122)
    - Genow House on North Road, 1898 (1980 reprint) (Folder 32, Box 122)
    - George Seaman, Harris Reynolds, Jim Wars and Eugene Adriance, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 33, Box 122)
    - 50 Hooker Ave, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 34, Box 122)
    - Hudson River Views [13 photos], 1891 - 1909 (1980 reprints) (Folder 35, Box 122)
    - Lent Plot, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 1, Box 123)
    - 8 Liberty Street, circa 1908 (1980 reprint) (Folder 2, Box 123)
    - Livingston House (destroyed by fire 1892) [3 photos], 1886 (1980 reprints) (Folder 3, Box 123)
    - Looking north from Kaal Rock, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 4, Box 123)
    - Main Street - river to 226, circa 1850 - circa 1929 (1980 reprints) (Folder 5, Box 123)
    - Main Street - 229-249, 1853 - 1917 (1980 reprints) (Folder 6, Box 123)
    - Main Street - 250-265, 1856 - circa 1930s (1980 reprints) (Folder 7, Box 123)
    - Main Street - 267-298, 1850 - 1915 (1980 reprints) (Folder 8, Box 123)
    - Main Street - 300-359 (Morgan House before and after fire), 1868 - 1917 (1980 reprints) (Folder 9, Box 123)
    - Main Street - 360-boot, 1893 - 1944 (1980 reprints) (Folder 10, Box 123)
    - Main Street - not numbered [7 photos], 1893 - 1917 (1980 reprints) (Folder 11, Box 123)
    - Manchester Bridge [2 photos], 1847 - 1913 (1980 reprints) (Folder 12, Box 123)
    - Mansion Street [2 photos], 1915 (1980 reprints) (Folder 13, Box 123)
    - Market Street - Adriance Memorial Library and banks [15 photos], 1891 - 1915 (1980 reprints) (Folder 14, Box 123)
    - Market Street - West Views [18 photos], circa 1901 - 1915 (1980 reprints) (Folder 15, Box 123)
    - Mid-Hudson Bridge under construction [6 photos], circa 1928 (1980 reprints) (Folder 1, Box 124)
    - Mill Street [13 photos], circa 1835 - 1917 (1980 reprints) (Folder 2, Box 124)
    - 130 - 132 Montgomery Street, circa 1912 (1980 reprint) (Folder 3, Box 124)
    - North and South Clinton Street [10 photos], 1897 - 1916 (1980 reprints) (Folder 4, Box 124)
    - North and South Hamilton Street [13 photos], 1890 - 1912 (1980 reprints) (Folder 5, Box 124)
    - Sash Bling Mill - taken before 1870 (formerly used by John Reed Lent as a plaster mill), undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 6, Box 124)
    - Schools [7 photos], 1906 - 1917 (1980 reprints) (Folder 7, Box 124)
    - Smith Street [2 photos], undated (1980 reprints) (Folder 8, Box 124)
    - Stable in rear of Nelson House Annex, 1913 (1980 reprint) (Folder 9, Box 124)
    - Vassar Hospital, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 10, Box 124)
    - Vassar Hospital - breaking ground for a new building, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 11, Box 124)
    - Van Kleek Hat Store - 259 Main Street [29 photos], 1850 - 1960 (1980 reprints) (Folder 12, Box 124)
    - Van Kleek House Interior - 49 South Hamilton Street [12 photos], undated (1980 reprints) (Folder 13, Box 124)
    - Washington Street [6 photos], circa 1909 - 1914 (1980 reprints) (Folder 14, Box 124)
    - Werner House, west of Christian Science Church - demolished 1914, undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 15, Box 124)
    - Winnikee Hall [4 photos], undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 16, Box 124)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs [6 photos], undated (1980 reprint) (Folder 17, Box 124)
  - Subseries 7.3: Education, 1866 - 1949; 7.3; Boxes: 124 - 125
    - The Collegiate School - depiction and description, undated (Folder 18, Box 124)
    - Eastman College Building, undated (Folder 19, Box 124)
    - Eastman College Building, undated (Folder 20, Box 124)
    - Eastman Business College - cabinet card of students outside building, undated (Folder 21, Box 124)
    - Eastman Business College - portrait of graduating class number 513, 1870 July 11 (Folder 22, Box 124)
    - Eastman Business College - Students, 1904 (Folder 23, Box 124)
    - First Intercollegiate Regatta (Railroad Bridge in background), 1895 (Folder 24, Box 124)
    - Intercollegiate Regatta Trophy [10 photos], 1949 (Folder 25, Box 124)
    - Poughkeepsie High School - Building, undated (Folder 1, Box 125)
    - Poughkeepsie High School - Sketch of woman, 1908 (Folder 2, Box 125)
    - Riverview Academy - Baseball Team, 1900 (Folder 3, Box 125)
    - Riverview Academy - Cadets, 1894 (Folder 4, Box 125)
    - Riverview Academy - Cadets, 1896 (Folder 5, Box 125)
    - Riverview Academy - Cadets, circa 1896 (Folder 6, Box 125)
    - Riverview Academy - Inspection Review, 1896 (Folder 7, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Cabinet card of A. Wars, class of 1888, circa 1888 (Folder 8, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Cabinet card labeled: UC Buildings, Vassar Brothers Lab, 1920 (Folder 9, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Cabinet card of woman playing tennis, Vassar Student Athletes, 1882 (Folder 10, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Class of 1886, circa 1866 (Folder 11, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Color photograph of Matthew Vassar artifact, undated (Folder 12, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Drawing of building, 1883 (Folder 13, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - Observatory, undated (Folder 14, Box 125)
    - Vassar College - The Studio at Vassar, undated (Folder 15, Box 125)
  - Subseries 7.4: Luckey, Platt and Company, 1919 - 1969; 7.4; Boxes: 125 - 126
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Airplane Delivery [12 photos], undated (Folder 16, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Christmas Car (for parade?), undated (Folder 17, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Employees (large group in street), 1919 (Folder 18, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Exterior [11 photos], undated (Folder 19, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Interior [15 photos], circa 1960s (Folder 20, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Interior [15 photos], circa 1960s (Folder 21, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Interior [12 photos], circa 1960s (Folder 22, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Interior (large mounted photo), 1909 May (Folder 23, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Large group of people, unknown (Folder 24, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Models [31 photos], 1944 - undated (Folder 25, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Sales Events [18 photos], 1942 - 1969 (Folder 26, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Sales Events [18 photos], 1942 - 1969 (Folder 27, Box 125)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Staff [38 photos], 1937 - 1969 (Folder 1, Box 126)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Thanksgiving Day Parade [20 photos], 1950 (Folder 2, Box 126)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Window Displays [16 photos], 1944 - circa 1947 (Folder 3, Box 126)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Window Displays [16 photos], 1944 - circa 1947 (Folder 4, Box 126)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Window Displays [17 photos], 1944 - circa 1947 (Folder 5, Box 126)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Window Displays [17 photos], 1944 - circa 1947 (Folder 6, Box 126)
    - Luckey, Platt and Company - Window Displays [16 photos], 1944 - circa 1947 (Folder 7, Box 126)
  - Subseries 7.5: The Stereoscopic Society, 1925 - 1929; 7.5; Box: 126
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1925 (Folder 8, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1925 (Folder 9, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1927 (Folder 10, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1927 (Folder 11, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1927 (Folder 12, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1927 (Folder 13, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1927 (Folder 14, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1927 (Folder 15, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, circa 1927 (Folder 16, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, circa 1927 (Folder 17, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, circa 1927 (Folder 18, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, circa 1927 (Folder 19, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, circa 1927 (Folder 20, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, circa 1927 (Folder 21, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1928 (Folder 22, Box 126)
    - The Stereoscopic Society, 1929 (Folder 23, Box 126)
  - Subseries 7.6: Miscellany, 1850 - 1981; 7.6; Box: 127 - 128
    - 18 Cabinet cards found in display case, circa 1884 (Folder 1, Box 127)
    - Display case with glass front that contained 18 cabinet cards, undated (Folder 2, Box 127)
    - 1st New York Volunteer Regiment, Company K mustering out portrait [3 copies, 1 large, 2 with names listed], 1898 (Folder 3, Box 127)
    - Andrew Davey Shop, undated (Folder 4, Box 127)
    - Arlington Apartments, La Grange Avenue, Town of Poughkeepsie, N.Y., undated (Folder 5, Box 127)
    - Billboards and houses [2 copies], undated (Folder 6, Box 127)
    - The Brown Derby, undated (Folder 7, Box 127)
    - Buildings in snow [2 copies], undated (Folder 8, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of Ada Von Aken [sp?], undated (Folder 9, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of baby, undated (Folder 10, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of Libbie Leach, 16 years old, undated (Folder 11, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of man, undated (Folder 12, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of unknown boy, undated (Folder 13, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of unknown man, undated (Folder 14, Box 127)
    - Cabinet card of unknown woman, undated (Folder 15, Box 127)
    - Collection of photographs of people gathered on Poughkeepsie streets, note suggests it concerns Franklin D. Roosevelt's burial, undated (Folder 16, Box 127)
    - Collection of Poughkeepsie Scenes, circa 1920s (Folder 17, Box 127)
    - Construction/mining equipment, undated (Folder 18, Box 127)
    - Dark photograph of man in paper frame, undated (Folder 19, Box 127)
    - Drawing of large building (Vassar?), with glass frame, 1865 (Folder 20, Box 127)
    - Edward's selling out sale, 381 Main Street, 1953 (Folder 21, Box 127)
    - Factory Building [?], undated (Folder 22, Box 127)
    - The Family Shoe Shop, undated (Folder 23, Box 127)
    - Fashion Shoe Shop, 209 Main Street; Verso: Freidman Bros., Abraham E.A. Herman, undated (Folder 24, Box 127)
    - Federal Button Company, undated (Folder 25, Box 127)
    - Fire-story corner building [2 copies], undated (Folder 26, Box 127)
    - French war tank at Vassar College, undated (Folder 27, Box 127)
    - House, undated (Folder 28, Box 127)
    - House on Fairview Ave, undated (Folder 29, Box 127)
    - Hudson River Day Line and Ferry to Highland under Railroad Bridge, undated (Folder 30, Box 127)
    - Icebreaker in Hudson River under Railroad Bridge, undated (Folder 31, Box 127)
    - Jim M. Evans Painting - Poughkeepsie city portraiture, circa 1850 - 1870 (Folder 32, Box 127)
    - Jim M. Evans Painting, documents found with painting, 1978 - 1981 (Folder 33, Box 127)
    - John H. Wiggers Building, undated (Folder 34, Box 127)
    - Kodak Projection Print Scale Photo Samples, undated (Folder 35, Box 127)
    - Large building with columns, undated (Folder 1, Box 128)
    - Large corner building, undated (Folder 2, Box 128)
    - Large House, undated (Folder 3, Box 128)
    - Large portrait of unknown man, undated (Folder 4, Box 128)
    - Large white building, undated (Folder 5, Box 128)
    - Lindmark bookstore interior on Liberty Street [1 photo, 1 negative], circa 1928 (Folder 6, Box 128)
    - Main Street lit [5 shots, 10 prints], undated (Folder 7, Box 128)
    - Man with building with glass roof, undated (Folder 8, Box 128)
    - Manufacturers' Association of Poughkeepsie, 1945 - 1946 (Folder 9, Box 128)
    - Mid-Hudson Bridge Construction, circa 1920s (Folder 10, Box 128)
    - Mid-Hudson Bridge Construction, circa 1920s (Folder 11, Box 128)
    - Mid-Hudson Industrial Association, 1947 (Folder 12, Box 128)
    - Minnewaska Falls, 1940 November 10 (Folder 13, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of Band in uniform, undated (Folder 14, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of Dorothy Lewis?, 1911 (Folder 15, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of family, seated, undated (Folder 16, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of Food/Grocery Store, undated (Folder 17, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of group of children with teacher?, undated (Folder 18, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of group of children with teacher?, undated (Folder 19, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of Horse and cart, 1916 (Folder 20, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of M. Schwartz clothing exhibit (backing damaged), undated (Folder 21, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of people on porch, undated (Folder 22, Box 128)
    - Mounted Photograph of unknown woman, undated (Folder 23, Box 128)
    - Nelson House, Poughkeepsie, NY - small photo, undated (Folder 24, Box 128)
    - Nude Woman, undated (Folder 25, Box 128)
    - N.Y., N.H. H.R.R. Station (New York, New Hampshire and Hudson River Railroad Station), undated (Folder 26, Box 128)
    - O'Hare's Pharmacy [3 different shop], undated (Folder 27, Box 128)
    - Old Cars Driving [2 copies], undated (Folder 28, Box 128)
    - Palmer's Ice Cream, undated (Folder 29, Box 128)
    - Palmer Rubber Company Inc., undated (Folder 30, Box 128)
    - Paper frame, undated (Folder 31, Box 128)
    - Parade, boy scouts?, undated (Folder 32, Box 128)
    - Parade at Main and Garden, undated (Folder 33, Box 128)
    - People in front of large white house, undated (Folder 34, Box 128)
    - Perlmutter Furniture Company [2 copies], undated (Folder 35, Box 128)
    - Photo of Two women in Newspaper, undated (Folder 36, Box 128)
    - Photograph of George Gunon [sp?], 1925 (Folder 37, Box 128)
    - Photograph of large house, undated (Folder 38, Box 128)
    - Photograph of small helicopter landing on baseball diamond, undated (Folder 39, Box 128)
    - Pierce-Ambler Co. Books and Stationary - 366 Main Street, undated (Folder 40, Box 128)
    - Polaroid of clock, with note and measurements, undated (Folder 41, Box 128)
    - Portrait of unknown man - with paper frame, undated (Folder 42, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Diner on Market and Church, undated (Folder 43, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie House [2 copies], undated (Folder 44, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Lion's club, 1957 (Folder 45, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Railroad Bridge before tracks dismantled, 1980 (Folder 46, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Shops [2 copies], undated (Folder 47, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Stores, undated (Folder 48, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Street Scene [3 copies, 2 negatives], 1928? (Folder 49, Box 128)
    - Poughkeepsie Street Scenes, 1960 (Folder 50, Box 128)
    - River Station, photo and history, undated (Folder 51, Box 128)
    - Schaffer Stores, undated (Folder 52, Box 128)
    - Shops along Main Street, undated (Folder 53, Box 128)
    - Smith Brothers Restaurant, 1928? (Folder 54, Box 128)
    - Snow Scene, Market Street, Poughkeepsie, undated (Folder 55, Box 128)
    - Socony Auto and Carriage Repairs [2 copies], undated (Folder 56, Box 128)
    - Socony, W.H. Horn's General Merchandise, undated (Folder 57, Box 128)
    - Traffic and road construction, undated (Folder 58, Box 128)
    - Train crossing Railroad Bridge (before Mid-Hudson Bridge) [2 copies], undated (Folder 59, Box 128)
    - Train Station [?], undated (Folder 60, Box 128)
    - Catharine Vassar grave in Poughkeepsie Rural Cemetery, undated (Folder 61, Box 128)
    - Vassar Farms caretaker's house, circa 1980s (Folder 62, Box 128)
    - View of Main Street, Poughkeepsie - cabinet card, 1869 (Folder 63, Box 128)
    - Miscellaneous scenes - bundled with negatives, 1981 (Folder 64, Box 128)
- 8. Administrative documents, 1992 - 2005; 8; Box: 129
  - Catalog of Archival Equipment, 2001 (Folder 1, Box 129)
  - Collection acquisitions, 1983 (Folder 2, Box 129)
  - Collection acquisitions, 1992 (Folder 3, Box 129)
  - Collection acquisitions, undated (Folder 4, Box 129)
  - Collection acquisitions, undated (Folder 5, Box 129)
  - Collection acquisitions, undated (Folder 6, Box 129)
  - Collection acquisitions, undated (Folder 7, Box 129)
  - Data CD containing scanned photographs and Jonah Sherman's powerpoint presentation, undated (Folder 8, Box 129)
  - Jonah Sherman's ID card from IBM Personal System/2 Forums, undated (Folder 9, Box 129)
  - Jonah Sherman's Original Collection Index, undated (Folder 10, Box 129)
  - Jonah Sherman's Original Collection Index (index cards), undated (Folder 11, Box 129)
  - Local Historical Information - Governmental Sources, Federal and State, undated (Folder 12, Box 129)
  - Local Historical Information - James Collingwood, undated (Folder 13, Box 129)
  - Local Historical Information -Poughkeepsie's Italian-Americans, undated (Folder 14, Box 129)
  - Local Historical Information - Poughkeepsie Savings Bank, 1994 (Folder 15, Box 129)
  - Local Historical Information - Selected Architectural Types in Dutchess County, undated (Folder 16, Box 129)
  - Local Historical Information Whales and Whaling and the Hudson River Whaling Ports, undated (Folder 17, Box 129)
  - Notepad from Jonah Sherman, undated (Folder 18, Box 129)
  - Photograph Transparencies, likely for speaking engagements, undated (Folder 19, Box 129)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal Special Section - 220 Years as the Valley's Journal, 1785 - 2005 (Folder 20, Box 129)
  - Slides for Presentation, undated (Folder 21, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1994 (Folder 22, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1997 (Folder 23, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2001 (Folder 24, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2002 (Folder 25, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2002 (Folder 26, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2002 (Folder 27, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2003 (Folder 28, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2005 (Folder 29, Box 129)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2005 (Folder 30, Box 129)
  - Miscellany, 1992 (Folder 31, Box 129)
  - Miscellany, 1997 (Folder 32, Box 129)
  - Miscellany, undated (Folder 33, Box 129)